# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我和大家分享
Today I’d like to share
# 葱的几种切法
Different ways to cut scallions.
# 在实际烹饪中大葱的绿色部分很少用上
In restaurant cooking, the green part of scallions is rarely used.
# 所以我们直接将其切掉
So we just cut and discard it.
# 首先我们展示第一种切法
The first method is
# 将大葱直接切成1厘米左右的小颗粒
To cut the scallion into small dices around 1 centimeter long （about 1/3 inch）
# 这种颗粒状的形态适合做爆炒类的料头
This shape and size is good for stir frying
# 或者用作宫保鸡丁的辅料
Or used in Kung Pao Chicken
# 下面我们来看成品展示
Now let’s see what it is like when I’ve done cutting it.
# 然后我们开始展示第二种切法
The second method of cutting scallion
# 此法更加的简单
Is even simpler
# 直接将大葱斜刀切成片
Just to cut the scallions with an angle
# 此切法的角度和厚度必须掌握一致
The key is to cut in the same angle and thickness
# 否则会很不均匀
To keep it evenly cut
# 此切法的大葱适用于葱爆羊肉或者葱爆类的做法
This cut of scallion is best for stir frying lamb
# 然后我们来看第三种切法
Here is the third method.
# 首先将大葱从中间切开一边
First, cut to the center of the scallion
# 同学们要注意不能把大葱对半切开
Yet not to cut it through
# 而只是切一边即可
Just cut it deep enough to the center
# 然后将大葱（翻）面朝下倾斜直刀切成细丝即可
Then open the scallion, turn it upside down, then thin slice it with angle.
# 这样的切法比较适合大众类的菜
This kind of slice is for most dishes.
# 或者用于京酱肉丝的垫底
Or use it as bottom part of a plate of Beijing Bean Paste Pork.
# 同样是切丝我们再来看第四种切法
Next we are going to learn the fourth way.
# 首先我们将大葱切成长段
First let’s cut the scallions into longer sections
# 同学们这一步直接决定葱丝的长度
The length is as shown.
# 然后再切开一边
Cut into the center of the scallions
# 我们首先来展示错误的方法
Now I will first show you the next step in the wrong way.
# 切开一边之后直接切丝
That after cutting into the center, I’ll keep thin slicing the whole thing.
# 在不去除内芯的情况下切出来的丝比较粗狂
It will end up not looking pretty.
# 下面我们再来尝试去掉中间的内芯
The right way is to remove the center of the scallions first.
# 去掉内芯之后重叠在一起顺着切成细丝
Then stack the outer part and cut, the slicing will be nice and easy.
# 这样切出来的大葱丝更加的规则细小
You’ll end up getting thin and even scallion threads.
# 它比较适用于炝锅或者蒸鱼
This kind of scallion is best for steaming fish, or first step of stir frying. （炝锅有统一说法没）
# 说到蒸鱼所用的所有辅料
To talk about steaming a fish
# 请大家继续往下看
We will be introducing how to prepare its seasonings
# 我们再准备小葱1小把切掉葱头
Get a bundle of spring onion, remove its white part
# 然后将小葱卷2圈
Roll the green part twice.
# 卷起来之后用手按住直刀切成细丝
Press the roll down firmly, then cut it thinly with no angle
# 切好之后放入碗中
Put it into a bowl
# 准备大红椒1个
Get one big red pepper
# 对半切开之后再去除辣椒籽
Cut in half and remove all the seeds.
# 然后去除辣椒中多余的“肉”
Removing the extra “meat”
# 这一步的目的是让辣椒变得更薄
In order to make the pepper slice even thinner
# 这样才能切出更加细的辣椒丝
we then can cut it into fine threads.
# 然后我们再准备生姜1小块
Get a small nugget of ginger
# 首先用垫刀切出薄片然后切成细丝即可
Thin slice it then cut it into very fine threads
# 鱼蒸好之后再将其撒在上面泼油即可
After the fish is steamed, put it on the top, then pour heated oil on it.
# 好了我的分享到此结束
That’s all for today.
# 如果你们还有感兴趣的小技巧
If you guys want to know other techniques
# 可以在评论区留言
Let me know in the comment area.